Francis J. O' Malley Papers
University of Notre Dame Archives
- Francis J. O'Malley: Manuscripts, CFOM
  - Teaching Records, 1934-1974; CFOM 2-22/, 29/; This series contains material relating to O'Malley`s activities as a member of the Notre Dame faculty (English Department).
    - Lectures and Speeches, 1930s-1970s; CFOM 2-13/, 29/; Texts, notes, and background material for class lectures and speeches to outside groups. The background material consists of articles, by O`Malley and others, and student papers. The lecture texts and notes are arranged alphabetically by tit
      - John Stuart Mill "John Stuart Mill, I: J.S.M. and the Utilitarianism (Benthamism)," Victorian Humanists lecture "J.S. Mill, II: The Congress of Humanity," lecture "Values in J.S. Mill," by E.J. O'Laughlin, student paper, CFOM 6/10
      - John Milton "The Rationalism of John Milton," speech delivered to the American Catholic Philosophical Association, April 12, 1950, St. Paul, Minnesota (page 6 missing), CFOM 6/11
      - John Milton Student paper, untitled, author unidentified, 12 pages and one page of bibliography. "The Metaphysics of Milton," lectures "The Failure of Milton the Poet," student paper used by O'Malley as a lecture "Milton on Education," student paper by R. Kennedy used by O'Malley as a lecture "Light Out of Darkness," unidentified student paper (1938), CFOM 6/12
      - John Milton "Milton's Protestantism," lecture "Milton's Ethics," lecture, CFOM 6/13
      - Miscellaneous Fragments Re: American literature, particularly Ambrose Bierce (one page) Re: The Christian in the World (two pages) Re: Erich Frank---Bibliographic note (one page) Re: Freud, Bergson--note (one page) Re: Pieper--bibliographic notes (one page) title page: "Religion and Modern Literature," (one page) title page: "Notes on Stravinsky," (one page), CFOM 6/14
      - Modern Catholic Writers "Lecture I: The World of Intellect and Art in the World of Worship" Student paper on Art and Scholasticism, re: Hopkins' Sonnet 34, author's name deleted "Modern Literature and the Religious Attitude to Life", CFOM 6/15
      - Newman "Newman and the Oxford Reformers and the Search for the Truth," Lecture I, The Victorian Humanists "The Tragedy of Newman" "The One Fold: The Development of Newman's Mind As Revealed in His Essay on the Development of Christian Doctrine," unidentified student paper, CFOM 7/01
      - "The Spirit of Newman," manuscript draft, CFOM 7/02
      - "The Thinker in the Church: The Spirit of Newman," manuscript draft, CFOM 7/03
      - "The Spirit of Newman," two manuscript drafts: one handwritten, one page typed, CFOM 7/04
      - "The Thinker in The Church: The Spirit of Newman," by Frank O'Malley, typed draft, handwritten noted on Newman, CFOM 7/05
      - "The Thinker in the Church: The Spirit of Newman," typed draft, CFOM 7/06
      - Nineteenth Century Novel and Novelists "The Nineteenth Century Novel: Jane Austin and Walter Scott," lecture "Dickens and Thackeray," lecture "English Fiction: The Eighteenth Century," lecture "The Mid Victorian Novelists," lecture "The Late Victorian Novel," lecture "Romantic Writers," title page only "Twentieth Century Fiction," lecture, CFOM 7/07
      - The Novel: Problems of Art and Morality--notes, CFOM 7/08
      - "The Renascence of the Novel", CFOM 7/09
      - Re: Willis Nutting, O'Malley's speech, CFOM 7/10
      - Paper delivered at faculty workshop- September 22, 1954- "How Teaching Can Be Made Personal and Individual", CFOM 7/11
      - "Fr. Charles O'Donnell, C.S.C.," lecture, 1954., CFOM 7/12
      - Peace Observance "Remarks by Professor Frank O'Malley at the Peace Observance," Notre Dame, January 28, 1973., CFOM 7/13
      - Peguy Lectures Student Papers "Work in Christian Culture: Gill and Peguy," by Sister Petra, O.S.B. "The Classical Man--Peguy," by Sister Marion, C.S.J. The Commonweal, Vol. XLII, No. 23 (September 21, 1945) Vol. LIII, No. 5 (November 10, 1950) "The Evangelism of Georges Bernanos," By Frank O'Malley, reprint The Review of Politics, Vol. 6, No. 4, (October, 1944) pp. 403-21., CFOM 7/14
      - Peguy: Lecture Notes, CFOM 7/15
      - Philosophy of English Literature "A Philosophy of English Literature," by Frank Cunningham, student paper used by O'Malley for lecture "The Philosophy of Literature III: Seventeenth and Eighteenth Century Backgrounds," outline "The Loneliness of Civilization: The Artist," lecture Philosophy and English Literature," student (?) paper, author unidentified, CFOM 7/16
      - Philosophy of Literature, "II. Plato," lecture, CFOM 7/17
      - Philosophy of Literature "III. Aristotle" "IV. Aristotle" "V." incomplete, pp. 4-9 "VI. Pseudo-Classical Criticism" (Probably parts of larger (student) thesis used by O'Malley as lecture material.), CFOM 7/18
      - Philosophy of Literature "The Meaning of A Catholic Art and Literature," unidentified student paper "A Philosophy of Literature," by J.H. Johnston. Reprinted from Concord, Vol. 2, No. 8, May 1949. "The Blood of Robert Lowell," by Frank O'Malley. Reprinted from Renascence, Vol. II, No. i, Fall, 1949. With handwritten note attached Handwritten notes by O'Malley on: Notre Dame helping the "thinker to perceive the church" Notre Dame as a Catholic university A non-Catholic educator, CFOM 7/19
      - Philosophy of Literature (continued) "Tolerance and Consensus," by Francis G. Wilson, University of Illinois. Typed manuscript of 32 pages. "Catholic Values in a Disintegrating World: The Renascence of the Novelist and the Poet," by Frances J. O'Malley, manuscript copy "Insertion: John Middleton Murry," two handwritten pages, CFOM 7/20
      - Philosophy of Literature "Lecture IIB. The Struggle between an Ethical or Theological Philosophy and a Scientific Philosophy" "Giordano Bruno, the Pantheist," lecture, CFOM 7/21
      - Philosophy of Literature "VII. Romantic Criticism (Part I)" "German Transcendentalist Philosophy" "Poetic Principle" "A Very Holy Devil," by R.J.J. Ames, student paper re: music, used by O'Malley as a lecture, ending in O'Malley's handwriting. "The Inner Death of Civilization and the Search for Unity," lecture. "The Average Man and The Classical Man," paper by unidentified author inserted within the above listed item (between pp.10 and 11) *This was apparently a talk given by O'Malley at Grailville, Loveland, Ohio, circa 1948. Information supplied to Stephan Bolger by Daniel J. Kane. "VIII. Romantic Criticism (Part II)" "The Romantic Ego,' by Russel Harris, student paper, 1941., CFOM 7/22
      - Philosophy of Literature "Philosophy and Twentieth Century Physicists," lecture, CFOM 7/23
      - Philosophy and Literature, "The Last Lecture English 99", CFOM 7/24
      - "The Plight of the Soul," The Review of Politics, July fragments., 1945/07; CFOM 7/25
      - O'Malley's Poetry "At Christmas" "Hodie Salvator Apparuit" "The King of Heaven" "The Saviour" "The Sun and the Shadow", CFOM 7/26
      - Poetry "The Renascence of Poetry," by Frank O'Malley, handwritten draft and one mimeographed page on "Some Notes About Poetry", CFOM 7/27
      - Rationalism "Philosophy of Rationalism: The Philosophy of Aristotle and St. Thomas," lecture, CFOM 8/01
      - Rationalism "Philosophy of Rationalism, Lecture I: Thomism" "A Footnote to the Problem of Rationalism: The Development of British Philosophy Through the Age of Reason', CFOM 8/02
      - Rationalism "Philosophy of Rationalism, Lecture IIIB: Seventeenth Century Materialism and Scientism", CFOM 8/03
      - Rationalism "The Philosophy of Rationalism and Neo-Classicism: A Summation Part I" "The Philosophy of Rationalism and Pseudo-Classicism: A Summation, Part II", CFOM 8/04
      - Realism and Naturalism "IX. Natural Science and Literary Theory", CFOM 8/05
      - Realism "The New Realism of Gissing and Meredith," lecture, CFOM 8/06
      - Reason and Intuition, notes, CFOM 8/07
      - Religion and Education "Some Thoughts on Religion and Education," homily by O'Malley, Second Sunday in Advent, CFOM 8/08
      - Religious Liberty "What is Religious Liberty?" speech, CFOM 8/09
      - "The Renascence of the Novelist and the Poet" Paper and correspondence with the Catholic Renascence Society and Loyola University Press regarding its publication. (See also "Catholic Values in a Disintegrating World), CFOM 8/10
      - Review of Politics: 20th anniversary dedication to Gurian and O'Hara, CFOM 8/11
      - E.M. Roberts "E.M. Roberts: The Physical and Metaphysical Fact and Vision" "A Place of Our Own," student paper, author's name deleted, CFOM 8/12
      - Romanticism (German): Fichte and Schelling "The Romantic Philosophy in Germany" "Schelling: Dreams and Mists and Rational Disaster" "Schelling: Summary" "The philosophical Support of Romanticism Lecture I: Romantic Spirit and the Fichtean Ego" "Fichte", CFOM 8/13
      - Romanticism Fichte and Hegel: lectures, CFOM 8/14
      - Romanticism Neo-Hellenism and Other Things "Hegel" "Fichte and Schelling", CFOM 8/15
      - Romantic Writers "The Romantic Disaster" "The Falsity of Shelley" "Shelley's Poetry, Part II", CFOM 8/16
      - Rousseau "Rousseau's Philosophy of Felling", CFOM 8/17
      - John Ruskin Note on William Morris "Ruskin: The Problem of Culture and Civilization", CFOM 8/18
      - Satire, notes, CFOM 8/19
      - William Setty Speech upon his leaving his position in the library, CFOM 8/20
      - "Snakes and Demons Strangling in a Fog," Address to the Wranglers May 25, 1949 (May 1958), CFOM 8/21
      - Herbert Spencer "Herbert Spencer I: His Synthesis of Knowledge" "Herbert Spencer: The Cloud of Unknowing," student paper, author unidentified, CFOM 8/22
      - Herbert Spencer "Spencer II: Spencer and George Eliot (and J.S. Mill, too)" Victorian Humanists lecture, CFOM 8/23
      - William Storey Statement Re: Storey's reception of the Sheedy Award, May 7, 1971, CFOM 8/24
      - Ruth Suckow, notes, CFOM 8/25
      - Jonathan Swift "Lectures I & II: His Chief Ideas" "III. Moral Realism", CFOM 8/26
      - Teaching "On the Administration of Teaching", CFOM 9/01
      - Teaching "Christian Perspective--Unity of Knowledge, notes, CFOM 9/02
      - Teaching- Papers delivered at Faculty Workshop, September 22, "The Kinds of Teaching," by Otto Bird "John Dewey on the Teacher's Function," by Father Leo Ward "How Teaching Can Be Made Personal and Individual," by Frank O'Malley 1954, CFOM 9/03
      - Teaching "How Teaching Can Be Made Personal and Individual" "On the Administration of Teaching," draft Outline notes for philosophy of literature (?), CFOM 9/04
      - Teaching "How Teaching Can Be Made Personal and Individual", CFOM 9/05
      - Teaching "Further notes on a Personalist Approach to College Teaching", CFOM 9/06
      - Teaching "Teaching in the Twentieth-Century Power World", CFOM 9/07
      - Teaching "Teaching in the Twentieth-Century Power World" speech given at the Danforth Fellowship Conference, September, 1957, CFOM 9/08
      - Tennyson "The Prophet of the Progress of Personality," Tennyson Lecture I, student paper, untitled, author unidentified, included within the lecture, CFOM 9/09
      - Twain Mark Twain, lecture notes, I-IV, CFOM 9/10
      - Sigrid Undset Thesis, author unidentified, 31 pages re: Sigrid Undset Chapter One: Inscape of Undset Chapter Two: The Reality of Sin Chapter Three: Senseless Sin Chapter Four: Idea of Man Chapter Five: Marriage Chapter Six: Art and Apologetics "The Conscious of Kristen," lecture "The Sin of Olaf of Hestiviken," lecture, CFOM 9/11
      - Sigrid Undset Lecture, CFOM 9/12
      - Sigrid Undset "Kristin Lavransdatter," page one of a (student?) paper "Sigrid Undset and the Christian Aesthetic," lecture "These Your Weapons," by Sigrid Undset "Sigrid Undset," Student Paper, author unidentified, O'Malley's notes and marginalia, CFOM 9/13
      - "Unity," speech, fragment (pp. 8-15) of larger work, CFOM 9/14
      - Victorian Humanists: Philosophy of literature Introduction, Lecture III: The Expert (incomplete), CFOM 9/15
      - Victorian Humanists: Philosophy of Literature Lectures "Subjects: Victorian Humanists" "Browning, lecture I: His Search into Man's Hearts" "Browning, lecture II: His Modernism" "Subjects in Carlyle" "Tennyson: A Failure, Lecture II", CFOM 9/16
      - Victorian Humanists: Philosophy of Literature Lectures "A New Tone in English Culture: Geology, Zoology, and Christology" "Late Nineteenth Century Cults", CFOM 9/17
      - Whitman "The Philosophy of Whitman", CFOM 9/18
      - Whitman "Whitman the Freeman" "Whitman: A Last Word", CFOM 9/19
      - "The Wisdom of the Word: The Value of Religious Knowledge for Modern Writers and Thinkers," by Francis J. O'Malley, CFOM 9/20
      - Thomas Wolfe American literature lecture, CFOM 9/21
      - Women Authors "Virginia Woolf: Some Introductory Remarks" "Willa Cather and the Modern Dilemma: Studies in Modern Culture" Notes on Elizabeth Madox Roberts "Katherine Mansfield and the Personal Sense of Truth" "Fraternity," student paper by Kelly Cook, CFOM 9/22
      - Virginia Woolf "Virginia Woolf: The Vast, the General Question: What is the Meaning of Life?", CFOM 9/23
      - Wordsworth, CFOM 9/24
      - World War II Notes for talk on war, CFOM 9/25
      - Jacques Barzun, "The Cults of 'Research' and 'Creativity,'" Harper's Magazine, October 1960., CFOM 10/01
      - Nicholas Berdyaev, "The Metamorphosis od Marxism' V.W., "Poetry and Intelligibility" G.M. Turnell, "First Steps in Modern Poetry", CFOM 10/02
      - Leon Bloy, "Salvation by the Jews" Transcript of one Bernanos letter, April 29, 1941, CFOM 10/03
      - John Michael Broderick, "A Strangeness of Day and Night," short story, CFOM 10/04
      - David Burrell, student paper on Graham Greene Unidentified student paper, CFOM 10/05
      - G.K. Chesterton, "The Arena", CFOM 10/06
      - Commonweal, May 27, 1955 re: Paul Claudel, CFOM 10/07
      - Paul Clemens, "Lamennais: Priest as Prophet", CFOM 10/08
      - Douglas Cole, Valedictory Address, June 1957, CFOM 10/09
      - Jean Danielou, "Marxist History and Sacred History", CFOM 10/10
      - Christopher Dawson, "The Dark Mirror", CFOM 10/11
      - Christopher Dawson, paper re: The Nature of Man, CFOM 10/12
      - Christopher Dawson, "The Study of Christian Culture As A Means of Education", CFOM 10/13
      - Francis X. Duggen, "Nicholas Berdyaev: The Philosophy of History", CFOM 10/14
      - T.S. Eliot, "Religion and Literature", CFOM 10/15
      - John Elson: student exams and papers Milton Fiske: student exams and papers, CFOM 10/16
      - Richard Giannone, "The Eternal Echo: Music in Death Comes for the Archbishop", CFOM 10/17
      - Romano Guardini, "The Scales of Live", CFOM 10/18
      - Romano Guardini, "On Power: Its Nature and Its Problems", CFOM 10/19
      - John Gerber, C.S.C.: student exams and papers, CFOM 10/20
      - John J. Gilligan, "The Visions of William Blake and Leon Bloy" B.A. Thesis Correspondence from Gilligan to O'Malley, CFOM 10/21
      - Albert Hemmenstede, O.S.B., "Benedictine Spirituality of Today," Orate Fratres, November 4, 1945., CFOM 10/22
      - Rayner Heppenstall, "A Context for Leon Bloy," Criterion, October 1936, CFOM 10/23
      - John G. Hessler, Valedictory Address, 1971, CFOM 10/24
      - Robert B. Heywood: student papers, CFOM 10/25
      - Lyle Joyce, "After Innocence," unpublished three-act play, CFOM 11/01
      - Helmut Kuhn, "Ecclesia Diabolica", CFOM 11/02
      - J. Lanigan, The Philosophy of English Literature, notes on readings, CFOM 11/03
      - Joseph F. Lanigan, "Poetry and Belief: The Splendor of Supernatural Form in the Poetry of G.M. Hopkins," B.A. Thesis 1943 (incomplete copy: used extensively by O'Malley in lecturing), CFOM 11/04
      - Liturgical Week, Bulletin No. 10, May 1942., CFOM 11/05
      - A. Manier: student paper and exam, CFOM 11/06
      - Ed Manier, "On the Question of Authority and Freedom in Society," Valedictory Address 1952, CFOM 11/07
      - Andre Maurois, "The Whirligig of History" Jacques Maritain, "A Note on Revolution", CFOM 11/08
      - Herbert Marshall McLuhan, "Baroque vs. the Dissociation of Sensibility", CFOM 11/09
      - John. C. Meagher, "The Windhover," student paper, CFOM 11/10
      - Alice Meynell, "The Unknown God", CFOM 11/11
      - Egbert Munzer, "Solovyev and the Meaning of History," Review of Politics, Vol.11, No.3, pp. 291-93, July 1949., CFOM 11/12
      - John Nef, "Religion and the Study of Man", CFOM 11/13
      - Gerhart Niemeyer, "Magician of the Screen", CFOM 11/14
      - Francis X. Newman, "Guardini and Bloy: Two Modern Catholic Minds", CFOM 11/15
      - Paul Anthony Orr, "The Artistic Principles of Gerard Manley Hopkins," M.A. Thesis 1949, McGill University, CFOM 11/16
      - Henry Peyre, "The Work of Paul Claudel", CFOM 11/17
      - Pius XII, excerpts, CFOM 11/18
      - Joseph F. Ryan, "Exile in the Theban Plays" Correspondence re: Publication of Ryan's article in The Review of Politics, CFOM 11/19
      - Elizabeth Sewell, "The Death of the Imagination," Thought, Autumn 1953, CFOM 11/20
      - Chester Soleta, C.S.C., "Coventry Patmore," student paper, CFOM 11/21
      - Vladmir Solovyof, "War and Christianity: From the Russian Point of View", CFOM 11/22
      - Vladmir Solovyof, "Short Narrative About Antichrist", CFOM 11/23
      - G.M. Turnell, "D.H. Lawrence," Colosseum, September 1935, CFOM 11/24
      - Mark Van Doren, poetry, CFOM 11/25
      - Matthew Arnold, unidentified student papers, CFOM 12/01
      - Bernanos, unidentified student thesis, chapters I, II, III, CFOM 12/02
      - Bernanos, "Bernanos: Whiplash of Mediocrity," unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/03
      - Bernanos and Bloy, unidentified students' papers, CFOM 12/04
      - Blake and Lawrence, unidentified student (?) papers, CFOM 12/05
      - Bloy, Thesis on Leon Bloy, incomplete, author unidentified, CFOM 12/06
      - Bloy and Bernanos, "A Study of Innocence," unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/07
      - Bloy, Bernanos, Claudel "The Spirit of Innocence," incomplete unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/08
      - Bloy and Kirkegaard, unidentified student papers, CFOM 12/09
      - Bloy, Mauriac, Claudel "The Christian Notion of Suffering and Personality," unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/10
      - Paul Claudel, unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/11
      - Dostoievsky, The Brothers Karamazov, unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/12
      - Emerson "Emerson, the Romantic Contradiction (sic) in Religion," unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/13
      - E.M. Forster, Identified students' reactions to E.M. Forster, CFOM 12/14
      - Franklin, Franklin, and Swift Identified and unidentified student papers, CFOM 12/15
      - Graham Greene, The Power and the Glory, unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/16
      - Gerard Manley Hopkins Student papers: unidentified and by Harold Williams, CFOM 12/17
      - G.M. Hopkins, unidentified student papers, CFOM 12/18
      - G.M. Hopkins, unidentified student papers, Mary Margaret Brown, "A Comparison of Robert Lowell and G.M. Hopkins", CFOM 12/19
      - D.H. Lawrence, "The Pulse of the Worlds,' unidentified student paper, CFOM 12/20
      - D.H. Lawrence unidentified student thesis, possibly used by O'Malley in his lecturing, CFOM 12/21
      - Liturgy, Excerpts from Vonier's "Key to the Doctrine of the Eucharist", CFOM 12/22
      - Thomas Mann "Life as Dead, Art as Life," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/01
      - Mauriac, unidentified student papers, CFOM 13/02
      - Mauriac and Claudel, unidentified student papers, CFOM 13/03
      - John Henry Newman, unidentified student papers, CFOM 13/04
      - "Personalism," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/05
      - The Philosophy of Literary Criticism Student Papers: unidentified and by Rodney Forbes and Garrett Bulger, CFOM 13/06
      - Poetry, unidentified student papers, CFOM 13/07
      - "Poets and Philosophers are Persons," unidentified (T.J.B.) student paper, CFOM 13/08
      - Alexander Pope "Alexander Pope and the Triumph of the New Philosophy," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/09
      - Power Pages 29-51 of larger work, author unidentified by extensively edited by O'Malley, CFOM 13/10
      - Romanticism "The American Romanticism," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/11
      - Spiritual Life Gerard A. Pottebaum, "Grace Is Everything," re: Bernanos & Greene Unidentified author, "The Church as the Bulwark of True Values," re: Guardini, CFOM 13/12
      - Spiritual Life, unidentified French manuscript, CFOM 13/13
      - Jonathan swift "Jonathan Swift's Rejection of the World in Gulliver's Travels," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/14
      - Verse "Climacteric," unidentified and incomplete student work, CFOM 13/15
      - "Victorian Humanism and True Humanism," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/16
      - "E.I. Watkin and T.S. Eliot on Culture," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/17
      - Whitman and Fichte "I, A Kosmos: Whitman and the Fichtean Doctrine of Personality," unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/18
      - Charles Williams, Descent Into Hell, unidentified student paper, CFOM 13/19
      - Unidentified fragment: possibly from a student paper, CFOM 13/20
    - Course Material, 1934-1962; CFOM 15/; Bibliographies, syllabi, records of assignments, outlines, and copies of exams (questions only).
      - College Rhetoric and Composition Assignments, CFOM 15/01
      - College Rhetoric and Composition, Records and Assignments, Winter Semester, 1945-46 and Spring Semester, 1946, CFOM 15/02
      - Committee on Academic Progress: Proposal and Notes, CFOM 15/03
      - Great Books Program: Introductory Explanation, CFOM 15/04
      - History of Civilization, Outline of the Roman System, 1934, CFOM 15/05
      - Humanities Neal M. Cross and Leslie Dae Lindou, The Search for Personal Freedom, Vol. I, A Text for a Unified Course in the Humanities, CFOM 15/06
      - Humanities Neal M. Cross and Leslie Dae Lindou, The Search for Personal Freedom, Vol. II, CFOM 15/07
      - Modern Catholic Authors: Bibliography, CFOM 15/08
      - Modern Catholic Authors: Exams, CFOM 15/09
      - Modern Catholic Authors: Paper Topics, CFOM 15/10
      - Modern Catholic Writers: Bibliography and Paper Topics Modern Catholic Writers: English 137 Syllabus, circa 1942 or 1943, CFOM 15/11
      - Modern Fiction and Modern Existence: Outline Bibliography, CFOM 15/12
      - Philosophy of Literature: Bibliography, CFOM 15/13
      - Philosophy of Literature II: 17th to 20th Centuries, Outline, CFOM 15/14
      - Philosophy of Literature, syllabus, CFOM 15/15
      - Social Thought Committee on Social Thought: Memorandum, CFOM 15/16
  - Financial Records and Personal Documents, 1928-1974; CFOM 23-25/; Tax records, commencement programs, academic degrees, awards, newspaper clippings relating to Malley's activities, his undergraduate grade reports, and similar items.
    - "The Christian Perspective of History," outline, CFOM 25/01
    - MESA, ed. Herbert Steiner, Autumn 1945. Copy presented to O'Malley by R.A. Reinhold, CFOM 25/02
    - Miscellany, CFOM 25/03
      - Richard Hertz, Chance and Symbol: A Study in Esthetic and Political Consistency, reviewer's (Robert B. Heywood) notes., CFOM 25/03
      - The Institute for Religious and Social Studies, pamphlet, 1949-50, CFOM 25/03
      - Francis Hanley's print "Dawn of Endless Day", CFOM 25/03
      - The University of Notre Dame Graduate School Requirements for the Preparation of Arts and Letters Dissertations, CFOM 25/03
      - List of Individuals, purpose unknown, CFOM 25/03
      - College of Arts and Letters Council Meeting Minutes, March 10, 1970., CFOM 25/03
      - Joaquin Balaquer's business card, CFOM 25/03
      - Bookmarks Index card re: McGrath, Rev. William, CFOM 25/03
      - Silver Jubilee of Rev. Thomas T. McAvoy remembrance, July 4, 1954, CFOM 25/03